Guide to the Persons and Russ family papers, 1903-2000.
Persons and Russ family papers, 1903-2000
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Persons and Russ family papers, 1903-2000.
6435
Anne J. Russ
3 Boxes
Letters, diaries, books
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Diaries, correspondence, and personal and professional files of Anne Julienne Russ, with the diaries and correspondence of some members of her family: her mother Doris Russ, her grandmother Persons, her grandmother Russ, and her great grandmother Lotridge. Doris Russ' diaries include passages about dealing with her cancer, and Anne's papers include personal reflections on the death of her mother. Also, several yearbooks, including: her high school yearbook, the Uptonian (Mount Upton, NY), where she was class president, plus the '54 Uptonian showing her mother, Doris Russ, an English teacher and librarian. The Anne Russ diaries include reflections on many aspects of her life, reading, work, and friends and her delight in her daughter.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of sociology and director of secondary education program at Wells College and mother of Dorinne Barbara Russ. Her teaching interests included the sociology of education, Latin America, and women's studies. She explored the ways ethnicity, class, and gender influcence organizations and institutions. Her education included a B.S., State University of New York at Cortland, M.A., Southern Methodist University, and Ph.D., Cornell University. Born July 21, 1937, Russ died from cancer on March 5, 2001.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Diaries, correspondence, and personal and professional files of Anne Julienne Russ, with the diaries and correspondence of some members of her family: her mother Doris Russ, her grandmother Persons, her grandmother Russ, and her great grandmother Lotridge. Doris Russ' diaries include passages about dealing with her cancer, and Anne's papers include personal reflections on the death of her mother. Also, several yearbooks, including: her high school yearbook, the Uptonian (Mount Upton, NY), where she was class president, plus the '54 Uptonian showing her mother, Doris Russ, an English teacher and librarian. The Anne Russ diaries include reflections on many aspects of her life, reading, work, and friends and her delight in her daughter.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Russ, Anne J.
Subjects:
Mothers and daughters.; Cancer--Patients.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Poem: "The Bonnet of White", 1849 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Geneology (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Autobiography- Anne Russ, Feb, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Photos (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Essays by Anne (about her Grandpa and Mom); news article (about Dick Russ), c. 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Clippings and Letters, 1951-1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Cover of "Baseball" Magazine (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Adoption and Naturalization of Dorinne Barbara Russ, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Scrapbook- (Mother) Doris- Syracuse University, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence: Doris Letters home from Syracuse University, 1928-1931 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence: Doris, 1928-1932 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence: Doris' letters home from Syracuse and first years of marriage in Ithaca, 1929-1935 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence: Doris' Letters home, 1929-1937 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Letters to Grandparents (Mr. and Mrs. C.B. Persons) from Anne and Dicky, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence: Grandma Russ to Anne, 1960s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Correspondence: Grandma Persons, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence: Mostly Don McEvoy, 1970-1980 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Correspondence: Friends, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Correspondence: Family/Friends, 1968-1980 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Correspondence: Relatives, 1970-1980; 1924 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Correspondence: Anne/ Anne & George (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Correspondence, 1968-1986 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Correspondence, 1968-1997 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Correspondence, 1968-1997 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 26)
- "Causes of the Civil War", 1954 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  (History essay by Anne)
- Anne Russ Philosophy of Education Diary, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- 1980 Cornell Commencement Program, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Miscellaneous folder (Box 1)
  NYC visitor info / Russ coat of arms/ historiography / Lincoln Center info
- Bennet High School Commencement Program (Buffalo, NY), 1927 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- "Uptonian 1974"- Mt. Upton Central School Yearbook (NY), 1974 (Box 1)
  Dedicated to Doris Russ
- "Uptonian 1955"- Mt. Upton Central School Yearbook (NY), 1955 (Box 1)
  Anne's Senior year
- "Uptonian 1954"- Mt. Upton Central School Yearbook (NY), 1954 (Box 1)
- "The Did"- Cortland State Teachers College Yearbook (NY), 1959 (Box 1)
  Anne's
- Travel documents wallet (Box 2)
  Receipts enclosed
- Driving Diary (Box 2)
- "Tales from Grimm" book, translated by Wanda Gag, 1945 (Box 2)
  Gift from parents, 1945
- Diary, 1958 (Box 2)
  Locked green book
- Diary, 1959 (Box 2)
  Florida trip and letters
- Diary of Hawaii, 1960-1961 (Box 2)
- Diary, 1961-1966 (Box 2)
- Budget, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
- Diary, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  Dallas, Mexico
- Diary, 1971 (Box 2)
  Marriage to Ron
- Date Book, 1972 (Box 2)
- Diary, 1972 (Box 2)
  "Eastfield College" notebook
- Funeral book- Doris P. Russ, Jul-73 (Box 2)
- Date Book, 1973 (Box 2)
  Includes Texas Drivers license and other miscellaneous papers
- Date Book, 1974 (Box 2)
- Diary, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
  Red date book
- Date Book, 1975 (Box 2)
- Diary, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
- Date Book, 1976 (Box 2)
  Tiny with photo on cover
- Date Book, 1976 (Box 2)
  Cornell- fall term 1976
- Journal- at Cornell, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
- Date Book, 1978 (Box 2)
- Diary; Letters from George in summer 1978; miscellaneous letters, 1978 (Box 2)
- Diary, 1978 (Box 2)
  Ithaca- olive patterned cover
- Date Book, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
- Diary, 1980 (Box 2)
- Date Book, 1980-1981 (Box 2)
- Diary, 1980-1982 (Box 2)
  Enclosed: Mexico trip notebook and book of poetry by Gowin
- Date Book and Miscellaneous, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Date Book, 1982-1983 (Box 2)
- Diary, 1982-1983 (Box 2)
  Tan with pink and blue flowers
- Diary, 1983-1985 (Box 2)
- Date Book, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
- Diary, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  Dorinne adoption
- Diary, 1987-1988 (Box 2)
  "Moonflower" design
- Diary, 1988-1991 (Box 2)
- Date Book, 1989-1990 (Box 2)
- Diary, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
  Red accordian style book
- Diary, 1992-1996 (Box 2)
- Date Book, 1998 (Box 2)
- Diary, 1997-1999 (Box 2)
  London trip- black and white cityscape design
- Guest Book (Box 3)
- Letter Box (Box 3)
  Miscellaneous letters- many to Anne, and section of letters from Anne in Hawaii to her family. Also, misc. photos and documents (Anne's 6th grade report card and later test scores)
- Diary - Sara (Lotridge?), 1904 (Box 3)
  Handwriting appears to match 1905 and 1906 diaries
- "Wedding Token" (marriage of Sara Lotridge and Elijah Russ), 1905 (Box 3)
  22-Nov-05
- Diary - Sara Lotridge (Anne's Great Grandmother), 1905 (Box 3)
- Diary - Mrs. E.D. Russ (Sara Lotridge- Anne's Great Grandmother), 1906 (Box 3)
- Diary - Sarah Lotridge, 1920-1922 (Box 3)
- Diary - Sara Lotridge (Anne's Great Grandmother- Mrs. Richard Lotridge?), 1926 (Box 3)
  Trip to California
- Diary - Sara Lotridge, 1926-1928 (Box 3)
- List of possessions- Mrs. C. B. Persons (Anne's Grandmother) (Box 3)
- Diary - Mrs. C. B. Persons (Anne's Grandmother), 1929-1930 (Box 3)
- Diary - Mrs. C. B. Persons, 1931 (Box 3)
- Diary - Mrs. C. B. Persons, 1932 (Box 3)
- Diary - Mrs. C. B. Persons, 1933 (Box 3)
- Diary - Mrs. C. B. Persons, 1934 (Box 3)
- Diary - Mrs. C. B. Persons, 1935-1936 (Box 3)
- Diary - Mrs. C. B. Persons, 1936-1937 (Box 3)
- Diary - Mrs. C. B. Persons, 1937 (Box 3)
- Diary - Mrs. C. B. Persons, 1938 (Box 3)
- Diary - Mrs. C. B. Persons, 1940 (Box 3)
- Diary - Mrs. C. B. Persons, 1940-1945 (Box 3)
- Diary - Mrs. C. B. Persons, 1945-1946 (Box 3)
- Diary - Mrs. C. B. Persons, 1947-1948 (Box 3)
- Diary - Mrs. C. B. Persons, 1948 (Box 3)
  Drive to Florida
- Diary - Mrs. C. B. Persons, 1949-1950 (Box 3)
- Diary - Mrs. C. B. Persons, 1951-1952 (Box 3)
- Diary - Mrs. C. B. Persons, 1953-1957 (Box 3)
- Diary - Mrs. C. B. Persons, 1958-1960 (Box 3)
- Diary - Mrs. C. B. Persons, 1961-1965 (Box 3)
- Diary - Mrs. C. B. Persons, 1966-1967 (Box 3)
- Diary - Mrs. C. B. Persons, 1966, 1968 (Box 3)
- Diary - Doris Russ (Anne's Mother), 1928-1931 (Box 3)
- Diary - Doris Russ, 1935-1938 (Box 3)
  Births and development of children, Dicky and Anne
- Diary - Doris Russ, 1965 (Box 3)
- Diary - Doris Russ, 1966 (Box 3)
- Diary - Doris Russ, 1967 (Box 3)
- Diary - Doris Russ, 1968 (Box 3)
  Doris' mother died, Anne's divorce
- Diary - Doris Russ, 1969 (Box 3)
- Diary - Doris Russ, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  Quit Smoking Diary
- Diary - Doris Russ, 1970 (Box 3)
- Diary - Doris Russ, 1971 (Box 3)
- Diary - Doris Russ, 1971 (Box 3)
- Diary - Doris Russ, 1973 (Box 3)
  Struggle with cancer (June 5- recieves diagnosis)